<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://iustinum.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://iustinum.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-04-24T04:53:11+00:00</updated><id>https://iustinum.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>Justin&apos;s Personal Blog </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Better Memories</title><link href="https://iustinum.github.io/blog/2023/better-memories/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Better Memories"/><published>2023-01-13T02:46:16+00:00</published><updated>2023-01-13T02:46:16+00:00</updated><id>https://iustinum.github.io/blog/2023/better-memories</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://iustinum.github.io/blog/2023/better-memories/"><![CDATA[<p>I have always thought of memories as something innate. This <a href="https://www.vox.com/even-better/23537229/improve-your-memory-concentration-tips">blog post</a> offers some good tips to sharpen one’s memory. Some techniques listed are:</p> <ul> <li>Avoid multitasking while remembering important things</li> <li>Assign vivid images to things you want to remember</li> <li>Allocate time to reflect on things you want to remember</li> <li>Become aware of forgetful moments</li> </ul> <p>There are two categories of memories. The first category are memories that carry emotional significance such as when someone got their dream offer. Those memories are hard to forget and therefore would not benefit much from memory improvement techniques.</p> <p>The second category are those that carry less emotional significance yet are important to remember. Examples include course contents for exams. Making those subjects more memorable would benefit from those tips.</p> <hr/> <h4 id="1-avoid-multitasking">1. Avoid Multitasking</h4> <p>Sometimes we forget important things simply because we did not pay attention while receiving them. We may be doing another task or being distracted. The easiest way to prevent such losses of memories is to pay attention to those important things.</p> <hr/> <h4 id="2-visual-associations">2. Visual associations</h4> <p>I always remember things better when they are visually intriguing. A beautiful scenery or face, a pleasant experience – those are all things that would last in my memories longer. If I want to remember where I left my car key, I would imagine the car key as a decoration of a piece of furniture. In associating visual significance to a nondescript object, we artificially increase its priority in our mental queue.</p> <hr/> <h4 id="3-reflection">3. Reflection</h4> <p>In elementary school, we are required to write a 800-word reflection if we violated school rule. The mechanical act of thinking about or writing down something that we would not want to remember help us mentally encode those memories.</p> <hr/> <h4 id="4-active-recollection">4. Active Recollection</h4> <p>I learnt about this technique from statistics teacher in high school. On any given day, he would quiz us contents from the previous day’s class. Here’s how I apply this technique on other parts of my life:</p> <ol> <li>I get exposed to the course material</li> <li>I would intentionally shift my mind to other tasks.</li> <li>When I am at the brink of forgetting those concepts, I will try to rewrite and summarize on what I had learnt without referencing the textbook.</li> </ol> <p>It was helpful when I tried to understand solutions to algorithm questions since rewriting solutions allows me to see the heuristic of the solution rather than the actual code itself.</p> <hr/> <blockquote> Many a man fails to become a thinker only because his memory is too good. —Friedrich Nietzsche </blockquote>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="neurohacks"/><category term="memory"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How do I remember things better?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New Year Resolutions (2023)</title><link href="https://iustinum.github.io/blog/2023/new-year-resolution-(2023)/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Year Resolutions (2023)"/><published>2023-01-13T00:46:16+00:00</published><updated>2023-01-13T00:46:16+00:00</updated><id>https://iustinum.github.io/blog/2023/new-year-resolution-(2023)</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://iustinum.github.io/blog/2023/new-year-resolution-(2023)/"><![CDATA[<p><strong><em>Note:</em></strong> I intentionally left some of those items vague so that I can explore around and refine my definition of those goals throughout the year.</p> <h4 id="self">Self</h4> <ol> <li>Write at least 500 words every day.</li> <li>Talk less; listen more.</li> <li>Don’t get easily satisfied.</li> <li>Maintain healthy sleep schedule.</li> <li>Work Smarter.</li> </ol> <h4 id="academic">Academic</h4> <ol> <li>Finish a major CS project</li> <li>Read five academic journals</li> <li>Solve at least one coding challenge everyday</li> <li>Learn C++ and Rust</li> <li>Fullstack development</li> </ol> <h4 id="health">Health</h4> <ol> <li>Do more cardio</li> <li>Strength training</li> <li>Less take-out</li> <li>More time outdoor</li> <li>Practice mindfulness</li> </ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="resolutions"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Note: I intentionally left some of those items vague so that I can explore around and refine my definition of those goals throughout the year.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Introduction</title><link href="https://iustinum.github.io/blog/2023/introduction-to-my-writeups/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introduction"/><published>2023-01-12T02:46:16+00:00</published><updated>2023-01-12T02:46:16+00:00</updated><id>https://iustinum.github.io/blog/2023/introduction-to-my-writeups</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://iustinum.github.io/blog/2023/introduction-to-my-writeups/"><![CDATA[<p>I enjoy reading and vocalizing my thoughts, but I struggle with writing. The more I write, the more I realize that I tend to repeat myself. I write in a weird style filled with vague words and grammar. I thought I could improve writing if I simply write more, but soon I found out that writing is more about thinking and translating those thoughts into words. <em>I struggle with writing because I cannot get my thoughts out in a linear fashion, which is why I always repeat myself.</em> It’s never too late to rethink how to improve my communication skills. This year, I finally mustered enough courage to start my own blog, with the sole purpose of improving my thinking and writing skills.</p> <p>With the advent of ChatGPT, one may ask, <em>what’s the purpose of writing?</em> I argue that writing has become even more paramount in the era of generative AI. As repetitive tasks get automated away, individualism and creativity are the minimum requirements for contributing anything unique. Creativity is one thing that cannot be automated away. Even tools such as DALL-E and ChatGPT requires prompt writing skills - tasks that involve creative human input.</p> <p>I will write about anything that piques my interests. I take inspirations from personal experiences, digital contents, and interpersonal conversations. I will prioritize on structuring my thoughts in a succint manner rather than experimenting with ostentatious writing styles. I welcome any feedback. You can reach me through my email at the homepage. When I look back in a few years, I would hope to see some improvements.</p> <blockquote> You don't write because you want to say something. You write because you have something to say. —F. Scott Fitzgerald </blockquote>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Why is writing important?]]></summary></entry></feed>